<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brett-Whitehead family history</title>
    <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Brett-Whitehead family history</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ellen Maccarmick Johns</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/ellen-maccarmick-johns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 12:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/ellen-maccarmick-johns/</guid>
      <description>Ellen was born in 1859 to Edmund Allen Johns and Clara Louisa Braginton.
See Ellen’s MyHeritage entry for more hints, and BMD birth records.
She was living with her mother as of the 1881 census, and married George Stawell that year.
In the 1891 census, she is living in Plymouth with her husband, a cook and a servant. For the 1901 census she is still living with her husband, and two different servants, but now in Great Torrington, Devon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Richard Braginton Johns</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/richard-braginton-johns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 12:56:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/richard-braginton-johns/</guid>
      <description>Richard was born on 18 October 1862 (also FamilySearch record to Edmund Allen Johns and Clara Louisa Braginton.
See the Richard Braginton Johns Ancestry.com page for more suggestions.
He married Mary Sherwin in 1889. Mary probably died in 1898.
In 1902 he married Georgiana Lucy Deacon
See this Wikitree page for Georgiana.
His household in Plymouth in the 1911 census is his wife, two children (see below) and a cook, two servants, a governess, a chauffeur and a stable boy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 10:33:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a history website for the family of John Brett and Margaret Joy Whitehead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alice Jane Braginton</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/alice-jane-braginton/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/alice-jane-braginton/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Bill Cooke for his sources on Braginton family history, see links on that page for details.
Alice Jane was born on 22 December 1845 (BMD record), and baptized on 13 February 1846, in St Giles on the Wood, Devon (source).
Martin Brett has an oak chest he inherited from Alice:
The chest has the following note inside:
Alice Jane married Samuel Henry Farwell Roe in 1890.
She died on 23 October 1929 (BMD record).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Braginton - Vicary</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/braginton-vicary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/braginton-vicary/</guid>
      <description>See this page on Braginton family history, and this page on Vicary family history.
 George Braginton, the oldest son of Richard Braginton, was baptised on 28 Feb 1808 in Ottery St Mary, Devon. On 13 Jan 1835, at St Giles in the Wood, he married Margaret Grace Vicary, the widow of William Cotton.
 Also Alice Braginton’s Genenet entry and links therein.
George Braginton was baptised on 28 Feb 1808, and died on 9 January 1886 (GRO Index Mar 1886 Plympton 5b 201).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Braginton family history</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/braginton_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/braginton_history/</guid>
      <description>See this page on Braginton family history:
 George Braginton, the oldest son of Richard Braginton, was baptised on 28 Feb 1808 in Ottery St Mary, Devon. On 13 Jan 1835, at St Giles in the Wood, he married Margaret Grace Vicary, the widow of William Cotton. Margaret Grace Vicary, the daughter of Thomas Cornish Vicary and Margaret Fry, was baptised at Great Torrington, Devon on 6 Dec 1807. Her marriage to William Cotton produced two children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brett - Howcroft</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/brett-howcroft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/brett-howcroft/</guid>
      <description>There is a Mary Ann Brett at this MyHeritage.com page that appears to match John Brett’s partner and Michael’s mother.
FeeBMD has no record of a marriage between “John Brett” and someone with surname “Howcroft” between 1840 and 1902. Christiana Payne’s biography notes that “as far as anyone has been able to ascertain, John Brett and Mary Ann Howcroft […] were never actually married.”
The record for John Brett’s household in the 1881 census records these household members at No 6 Keswick Road, London:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brett - Lee</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/brett-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/brett-lee/</guid>
      <description>Data for the family of Michael Brett and Nellie Mary Lee.
They married in 1902 - see BMD record.
Michael’s census record for 1911 shows him to be living in Hangerlea, Stansted Road, Bishop’s Stortford, with this household:
  Name Age    Michael Brett 39  Nellie Mary Brett 29  Joan Brett 8  John Brett 6  Peter Brett 1  Tirzah Faulder 25  Caroline Alice Hudgell 24  Annie Amelia Smith 27    Martin Brett described Nellie (“Granny Brett”) as “wonderfully accommodating”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brett - Pilbean</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/brett-pilbean/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/brett-pilbean/</guid>
      <description>These are notes for the family of Charles Curtis Brett and Ann Pilbean.
See Charles Curtis Brett’s wikitree entry. This says that he married Ann “Pilbin” on 12 June 1823. The Dictionary of National Biography has this as “Pilbean”, and Ann’s birth year as 1808/9 - see page on John Brett (painter).
Charles Curtis Brett’s household in the 1851 census:
  Name Age Relation Profession    Charles C Brett 67 Head Vetinary surgeon ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brett - Whitehead</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/brett-whitehead/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/brett-whitehead/</guid>
      <description>Note for the family of John Brett (b 1905) and (Margaret) Joy Whitehead.
They married on 5 May 1928. See also BMD record.
John and Joy had three children:
 Sue Oliver (Malta, 24 May 1929 — 21 March 2021). Jenifer Brooke-Smith (Portsmouth, September 1931). Martin Brett (Woolwich 6 January 1939).  See BMD records.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke&#39;s Peerage on Whitehead family</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/burkes_whitehead/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/burkes_whitehead/</guid>
      <description>See this Whitehead extract from Burke’s peerage, 1949 for a full summary of the Whitehead family tree to 1949.
Quoting from that extract:
 Gilbert Hinds, b. 26 May, 1866 ; to. 10 April, 1901, •Helena Emmeline, (New Raven, Eltham, Kent), only dau. of late Henry A. Langford, of Plymouth, and d. 18 Dec. 1908, leaving issue,  Margaret Joy, m. 5 May, 1928, Lt.-Cmdr. John Brett, D.S.C., R.N., elder son of Michael Brett, of Bishop’s Stortford, and has issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charles Curtis Brett</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/charles-curtis-brett/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/charles-curtis-brett/</guid>
      <description>See Charles Curtis Brett’s wikitree entry.
 Grandfather: Curtis Brett (b ~1720), printer. CB wikitree entry. CB will. Biography as printer in Jamaica. His children were Charles Richard Brett (born and died 1761) and Curtis Brett (b 1765) Father: Curtis Brett (b 1765). CB Jr wikitree entry.  Charles Curtis married Ann Pilbean in 1823.
 … Charles Curtis Brett, had a background in both the army and the navy. He served as a midshipman on HMS Egmont, a 74-gun warship, between 1816 and 1823.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clara Louisa Braginton</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/clara-louisa-braginton/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/clara-louisa-braginton/</guid>
      <description>Clara Louisa’s parents were George Braginton and Margaret Grace Vicary.
Also see this page on Braginton family history.
From that page: Clara Louisa’s father was a shipowner, and probably named one of his ships “Clara Louisa” after his daughter.
Clara was born on 7 May 1837, and baptized in St Giles in the Wood church, Devon on 20 July 1937 (many thanks to Bill Cooke for this information, and the scan below of Clara’s baptismal register:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeBMD / GRO records</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/bmd_records/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/bmd_records/</guid>
      <description>These are UK birth, marriage and death records from searches on https://www.freebmd.org.uk, or directly from the UK General Record Office.
Births   Period Surname First name(s) Mother District Vol Page Notes    Dec 1837 BRAGINTON Louisa  Launceston 9 125   Mar 1846 BRAGINTON Alice Jane  Torrington 10 325   Sep 1931 Brett Jenifer Whitehead Portsmouth 2b 771   Mar 1939 Brett Martin Whitehead Woolwich 1d 1299 6 January 1939  Mar 1903 Brett Joan  Hendon 3a 220   Dec 1872 BRETT Michael  Dorking 2a 137   Jun 1910 BRETT Peter  B Stortford 3a 759   Mar 1865 Johns Edmund Allen  Torrington 5b 549   Mar 1859 JOHNS Ellen Macarmick  Torrington 5b 481   Jun 1868 LANGFORD Albert Leonard  Plymouth 5b 265   Dec 1837 LANGFORD Henry Albert  Liskeard 9 138   Sep 1856 Roe Samuel Henry Farwell  Camelford 5c 10   Sep 1905 Whitehead Margaret Joy  Lewisham 1d 1131     Marriages   Period Surname First name(s) Spouse surname District Vol Page Notes    Jun 1928 Brett John Whitehead Lewisham 1d 2117   Mar 1902 Brett Michael  Wandsworth 1d 929   Mar 1857 Johns Edmund Allen  Torrington 5b 793   Jun 1866 LANGFORD Henry A  Plymouth 5b 437   Jun 1890 Roe Samuel Henry F  Portsea 2b 942   Jun 1901 Whitehead Gilbert Hinds  Truro 5c 237     Deaths   Period Surname First name(s) Age District Vol Page Notes    Dec 1943 Brett Michael 72 Newton A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gilbert Hinds Whitehead</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/gilbert-hinds-whitehead/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/gilbert-hinds-whitehead/</guid>
      <description>According to a Peerage.com page on Sir James Whitehead, Gilbert Hinds Whitehead was the fifth child (and third son) of Sir James Whitehead, 1st Baronet and Mercy Matilda Hinds.
He was born 26th May 1866, and married Helena Emmeline Langford in 1901.
In 1890, he became a Liveryman of the Worshipful Company of Fruiterers and a Freeman of the City of London — see his profile in the archives of the Worshipful Company of Fruiterers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helena Emmeline Langford</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/helena-emmeline-langford/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/helena-emmeline-langford/</guid>
      <description>Martin Brett tells me that “Granny Whitehead” preferred “Emmeline”.
Her birth certificate gives her date of birth as 10 May 1872. She was born at home, at 5 Hill Park Crescent, in Plymouth.
Emmeline’s parents were Henry Albert Langford and Clara Louisa Braginton.
See also Whitehead family grave and Whitehead extract from Burke’s peerage.
In the 1881 census, Helena Emmilina Langford was at 5 North Hills Terrace, in the following household:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry Albert Langford</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/henry-albert-langford/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/henry-albert-langford/</guid>
      <description>Henry Albert was probably born in Liskeard in late 1837 (BMD record).
He married Clara Louisa Johns (née Braginton) in 1866.
His daughter’s birth certificate gives his profession as “general merchant” in 1872. His probate and death certificate (see below) gives his profession as “accountant”.
There is a grave for “Henry A Langford” in St Mary’s Church, Callington, Cornwall, with inscription:
 Henry A Langford who departed this life June 24th 1879, aged 41 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Brett (b 1831)</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/john-brett-1831/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/john-brett-1831/</guid>
      <description>See John Brett’s wikipedia entry
The Dictionary of National Biography (1912) on John Brett (the painter). “BRETT, JOHN (1831–1902), landscape painter, born at Bletchingley, Surrey, on 8 Dec. 1831, was eldest son of Captain Charles Curtis Brett of the 12th lancers by his wife Ann Philbrick. […] He died in his house at Putney on 8 Jan. 1902. He married in 1870, and had four sons and three daughters who survived him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Brett (b 1905)</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/john-brett-1905/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/john-brett-1905/</guid>
      <description>John died in World War 2, when his ship HMS Gloucester sank, on May 22nd 1941.
He was born on 27 March 1905 (see Peerage.com article).
He married Margaret Joy Whitehead on 5 May 1928.
John’s parents were Michael Brett and Nellie Mary Lee. Michael was the eldest son of John Brett, the painter.
He was commissioned into the Royal Navy on 15 September 1918, and gained these ranks:
 Midshipman: 15 January 1923 Sub-Lieutenant: 15 November 1925 Lieutenant: 15 November 1927 Lieutenant-Commander: 15 November 1935.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Brett: Pre-Raphaelite Landcape Painter</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/payne_john_brett/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/payne_john_brett/</guid>
      <description>A biography of John Brett:
 John Brett
Pre-Raphaelite Landscape Painter
Christiana Payne
September 21, 2010, Yale University Press
304 pages, 9.5 x 11
ISBN: 9780300165753
 See the Yale University Press page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johns - Braginton</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/johns-braginton/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/johns-braginton/</guid>
      <description>Family page for Edmund Allen Johns and Clara Louisa Braginton.
They married in 1857. See their marriage record transcription, and the BMD record.
From the page above, and the census records below, and that listed in Helena Emmeline Langford’s page, Clara Louisa and Edmund Allen had at least three children:
 Ellen Maccarmick Johns (1859 — 1938). Richard Braginton Johns (1862 — 1952). Edmund Allen Johns (1865 - 1929).  Bill Cooke (see below) tells me that Edmund Allen Johns (the father) was baptized on 21 Sep 1830 in Gerrans, Cornwall, England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Langford - Braginton</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/langford-braginton/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/langford-braginton/</guid>
      <description>Henry Albert Langford married Clara Louisa Johns (née Braginton) in 1866, in Plymouth (BMD record).
The couple probably had two children:
 Albert Leonard (1868-1879) (see below). Helena Emmeline (1872-1949).  Albert Leonard Langford Apart from Helena Emmeline, there was only one other Langford born in Plymouth between 1864 and 1890 - Albert Leonard Langford, in 1868 (BMD record).
Albert Leonard Langford died at age 11, in 1879, soon after his father, after “accidentally falling over the side of a quarry”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Margaret Joy Whitehead</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/margaret-joy-whitehead/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/margaret-joy-whitehead/</guid>
      <description>Margaret Joy went by “Joy”.
Joy was born on 12 June 1905 (see BMD records for birth and death).
Her parents were Gilbert Hinds Whitehead and Helena Emmeline Whitehead.
She married John Brett in 1928, and had three children.
John died in 1941. Joy married Robert Clement Giles in 1965 (see Whitehead extract from Burke’s peerage). Robert Clement Giles was a staff officer in intelligence in Hong Kong when it fell to the Japanese in 1941, and was a prisoner of war until 1945.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marriage certificate transciption for Johns-Braginton</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/marriage_johns_braginton/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/marriage_johns_braginton/</guid>
      <description>From this Cornwall OPC database using search “Clara Braginton”:
    Field Value    Day Month 08-Jan  Year 1857  Parish Or Reg District St. Giles in the Wood, Devon  Groom Fn Edmund Allen  Groom Sn JOHNS  Groom Age upwards of 21  Groom Residence Gerrans  Groom Condition B  Groom Rank Profession Gentleman  Groom Signed / Marked (S/M) S  Bride Fn Clara Louisa  Bride Sn BRAGINTON  Bride Age 19 but under 21  Bride Residence St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marriage certificate transciption for Whitehead-Langford</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/marriage_whitehead_langford/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/marriage_whitehead_langford/</guid>
      <description>From this Cornwall OPC database using seach “Helena Langford”.
  Field Value    Day Month 10-Apr  Year 1901  Parish Or Reg District Michael Penkevil, St.  Groom Fn Gilbert Hinds  Groom Sn WHITEHEAD  Groom Age 34  Groom Residence Wilmington Manor, Kent  Groom Condition Bachelor  Groom Rank Profession Art Printer  Groom Signed / Marked (S/M) S  Groom Father Name James, Sir, Bart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Brett</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/michael-brett/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/michael-brett/</guid>
      <description>From Christiana Payne’s biography of John brett p 109, Michael born on July 1871.
See Michael’s Wikisource data. This suggests his BMD birth record.
His parents were John Brett and Mary Howcroft.
Michael Brett married Nellie Mary Lee.
There is a page on Michael at ancestry.co.uk.
He died on 9 December 1943, with probate:
 BRETT Michael of Hangerlea Stansted-road Bishops Stortford Hertfordshire died 9 December 1943 at Teignmouth Devonshire Probate Llandudno 17 April to Nellie Mary Brett widow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MyHeritage entry for Mary Ann Howcroft</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/mh_mary_howcroft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/mh_mary_howcroft/</guid>
      <description>There is a Mary Ann Brett at this MyHeritage.com page that appears to match John Brett’s partner and Michael’s mother.
 Mary Ann Brett, Brett (born Howcroft) was born on month day 1843, at birth place, to William HOWCROFT and Mary Anne HOWCROFT (born HALL).
William was born in 1791, in Yorkshire, England.
Mary was born on April 21 1815, in Worthing, Sussex, England.
Mary was baptized on month day 1844, at baptism place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roe - Braginton</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/roe-braginton/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/roe-braginton/</guid>
      <description>The family of Samuel Henry Farwell Roe and Alice Jane Braginton.
They married in 1890 (BMD record).
It seems they had no children. Alice Jane was 44 when they married.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samuel Henry Farwell Roe</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/samuel-henry-farwell-roe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/samuel-henry-farwell-roe/</guid>
      <description>See Farwell Roe Genenet page.
Samuel Henry Farwell Roe was born in 1856 (BMD record). He was the son of the Reverend Henry Farwell Roe, Rector of Lesnewth, Cornwall, and Isabella Messenger (source).
Roe married Alice Jane Braginton in 1890.
Farwell was vicar at Zennor, Cornwall from 1888 to 1900. From this blog on an historical diary about Saint Senara’s church at Zennor:
 However, by the late 19th Century the Church had become neglected and when the Reverend Samuel Henry Farwell Roe became Vicar in 1888 he realised it was in need of restoration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vicary family history</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/vicary_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/vicary_history/</guid>
      <description>William Cooke sent much of the information on this page, including the transcription of the Vicary family bible. Thank you to him, for his great generosity in sharing his research, and his care in doing it.
Quoting the transcript:
 1835 - Jan 13th. The above named Margaret Grace Relict of the above named William Cotton was married in the Church of St. Giles in the Wood - Devon - to George Braginton Son of Richard Branginton &amp;amp; Anne his wife</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whitehead - Langford</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/whitehead-langford/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/whitehead-langford/</guid>
      <description>About the family of Gilbert Hinds Whitehead and Helena Emmeline Langford.
See Whitehead extract from Burke’s peerage for full summary of Whitehead family tree to 1949. From that source, the couple:
 Married on 10 April 1901 (source above). had one child, Margaret Joy, in 1905 (BMD record).  See transcription of full marriage record, and BMD record.
Gilbert Hinds Whitehead died in 1908.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whitehead family grave</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/whitehead_grave/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/whitehead_grave/</guid>
      <description>This site about a gravesite for the Whitehead family has the following information:
 Gilbert Hinds Whitehead
Third son of Sir James Whitehead. Bart.
Born 26th May 1866, died 18th December 1908
Helena Emmeline, wife of the above
Born 10 May 1872, died 18 Oct 1949
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>William Cooke and the Braginton / Vicary families</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/cooke_braginton_vicary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 17:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/cooke_braginton_vicary/</guid>
      <description>William (Bill) Cooke kindly sent a great deal of carefully sourced information the Braginton and Vicary families. He has a particular interest in the history of some Devon parishes, in particular, the parishes of St Giles in the Wood, High Bickington, Atherington, Tawstock and Yarnscombe.
Bill sent the wonderful transcription of the Vicary family bible, a detailed summary of Braginton family history, and Clara Louisa Braginton’s baptismal record.
He also very generously allowed me (Matthew Brett) to share this information on the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/roe-braginton-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/roe-braginton-notes/</guid>
      <description>Reverend Samuel Henry Farwell Roe
Births Sep 1856 (&amp;gt;99%) Roe Samuel Henry Farwell Camelford 5c 10
Deaths Mar 1943 (&amp;gt;99%) ROE Samuel H F 86 Barnstaple 5b 567
A grave from Marlborough Road Cemetery, Ilfracombe, Devon:
https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/124810872/farwell-roe
““” Sacred to the memory of Revd Farwell Roe died 19th March 1943
Also of Jane Roe, his wife, died 23rd February 1948.” ““”
Deaths Mar 1948 (&amp;gt;99%) Roe Jane 69 Barnstaple 7a 293</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edmund Allen Johns</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/edmund-allen-johns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/edmund-allen-johns/</guid>
      <description>Edmund Allen was born on 31 May 1865 to Edmund Allen Johns and Clara Louisa Braginton.
See also BMD birth records.
He was born six months months after the death of his father, also Edmund Allen, who died on 2 December 1864 (see above).
There is only one marriage for an Edmund Johns in Bideford, in 1896, in a search from 1880 to 1929.
There is a 1930 probate entry for Edmond Allen:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking to Martin Brett</title>
      <link>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/talk_to_martin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthew-brett.github.io/brett-whitehead/talk_to_martin/</guid>
      <description>Conversation between Matthew and Martin Brett, 10 May 2020 Helena Emmeline preferred “Emmeline”.
Emmeline lived with “Aunt Alice” and an unfriendly vicar in Zennor, in Cornwall. She (Granny Whitehead) would do an impression of the thick accent of the postman.
A distant relative, surname Johns, gave a significant amount of money to Emmeline in his will, enough to buy a car.
Another conversation maybe in June Joan, John and Peter Brett were the three children of Michael Brett and Nellie Mary Lee.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
